courtauld.ac.uk 2019-08-29

# None

The Courtauld Institute of Art is committed to protecting your privacy. This statement applies to all information collected or submitted on the Courtauld Institute of Art’s website, and is made in the light of the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in order to alert you to the practices which govern the processing of your data.

### The information we collect

We collect the following information from people visiting the website:

  * Information on how people use the site
  * Your name and email address if you sign up for an [enewsletter](https://courtauld.ac.uk/gallery/stay-in-touch)
  * Your name and payment details when you [buy gallery merchandise](http://www.courtauldshop.com/), pay for one of our [events](https://courtauld.ac.uk/research/research-forum/events) and [courses](https://courtauld.ac.uk/learn/art-history-short-courses), or [donate online](https://courtauld.ac.uk/support/give-now)
  * Visitors’ external IP addresses, details of which browser they used and on what kind of machine (eg Windows/Mac)
  * Information relating to user demographics and interests using users’ Google advertising IDs. This data is not personally identifiable.

### How we collect the information

We collect that information about users of this site in four different ways:

  * Cookies
  * Online forms
  * Online payments
  * Server logs

**Cookies**  
We use small data files stored on your computer called ‘cookies’. Most big websites do this. They help us improve the website experience for you. Find out what we use them for, and how to control their use on our [cookies page](https://courtauld.ac.uk/about/policies/cookies).

**Online forms  
**Forms such as the [enewsletter form](https://courtauld.ac.uk/gallery/stay-in-touch) collect data from users of the site. In this instance the user volunteers their personal information and the information is held in accordance with our Data Protection Policy.

**Online payments  
**All money transactions on our website are operated by trusted third parties using secure servers. They take appropriate measures to ensure that the information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

**Server logs  
**The web server is the computer that this website sits on. When you click on a link to a web page, you are sending a request to the server for that page, and all files associated with it (eg images on the page). The server keeps a log of all these requests and records other information such as the time and date of each request. It also registers whether the requested files could be found on the server.

This information is useful for us because it tells us how popular certain parts of the site are, and whether there is a problem with broken links (usually signalled by a 404 error, or the message ‘files not found’). The logs do not identify individual users, and we do not try in any way to identify users through correlating the log files with other data.

### How we use the information

Any information we collect is used to:

  * Improve the content and design of the website
  * Measure our marketing activities
  * Contact visitors (with their permission) with information relating to the Courtauld
  * Confirm payment with your credit or debit provider

We never share your information with other organisations for marketing, market research or commercial purposes, and we don’t pass on your personal information to any other website. The following links can be used to opt out of Google Analytics data collection and Google advertising data respectively:

<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

<http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>.

For more exhaustive protection against your data being collected, consider using a tool such as EasyPrivacy.

### Other websites

This site contains links to and from websites of other organisations and satellite sites operated by Courtauld staff. This privacy policy only applies to the main Courtauld Institute of Art site.

**Following a link to another website**

If you go to another website from this one, please read the privacy policy on that website if you want to know what it does with your information.

**Following a link to courtauld.ac.uk from another website**

When you come to the Courtauld Institute of Art’s website from another site, we may get personal information about you from the other website. You should read the privacy policy of websites you visit that link you to this one if you want to know about this.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please e-mail us at [website@courtauld.ac.uk](mailto:website@courtauld.ac.uk)
